ABDULLAH HASHIM

+966-595585131 | Abdullah97Hashim@gmail.com | Saudi Arabia, Yanbu (Willing to relocate)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdullah-hashim/

SUMMARY

A Self-starting, intellectually curious and creative Computer Science student with proven experience in User Interfaces Development, Software Development, and Web Development. Able to apply UI/UX concepts to improve the usability for the users, and delivering full projects within the provided time frame.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SAUDI ARAMCO | COOP INTERN | JUL 2018 - JAN 2019 | Saudi Arabia, Dhahran

EXPEC Computer Center - Petroleum Engineering Application Services Department Reservoir Engineering Systems Division

- Designed and developed a new web application, and several general use components using Angular framework
- Analyzed users' engagement with the applications and developed ways to improve the overall user experience
- Exposed to oil and gas business analysis models in order to grasp the business model and enhance the applications experience

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

THE SEARCH BASE | Co-Founder & Software Developer | Jul 2018 - Now | UK, Cardiff

TheSearchBase is startup where it sells a software as service (SaaS) that helps companies to market their recruitment services using our smart chat-bot application

- Developed the workflows inside the team which enhanced the productivity by 43%
- Migrated the project to a modern framework (React.js) which increased the delivering time and code robustness
- Took care of all user interfaces and interactions in the application, by improving the application interactivity.

AWARDS & ACTIVITIES

WA'ED HACKATHON | SECOND PLACE | Dec 2018

Won the 2nd place among 150 participants over the kingdom in the parking solutions challenge

- Led the team during the hackathon
- Collaborated in designing the business model and analyzing the market size
- Prototyped and presented the idea

SAUDI ARAMCO UPSTREAM HACKATHON | FIRST PLACE | Dec 2018

Won the first place among 107 participants in the Automated Seismic Data Interpretation

- Designed an algorithm to automate seismic interpretations
- Utilized seismic attributes in the automation

EDUCATION

YANBU UNIVERSITY COLLEGE | SEP 2014 - MAY 2019

Bachelor of Computer Science with a GPA (3.5/4) - Web Application Development Track

Wire-framing
Flowcharts

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML CSS Javascript
- Angular 6 Framework
- React Framework
- Adobe XD

Photoshop

- Data Analysis
 - Image Processing
- Python Flask
- Nodejs Express
- MySQL

COURSES

FULLBRIDGE U ONLINE AT MISK | DEC 2017

Fullbridge intensive course which mainly included:

Creative problem solving skills, Data analysis technologies, and Project planning